

# BENJAMIN WHITE

WEB DEVELOPER

# CONTACT

Nashville, TN

(502) 794-2449
benwhite89@icloud.com
github.com/BenWhite89
linkedin.com/in/benjaminwhite89

## PROFILE

I am a driven web developer with a strong background in data analysis and process optimization. Experienced in working on large projects, identifying client needs, and communicating across a large enterprise. Well-versed in SQL, Javascript, and front-end design. Extremely motivated to learn and grow.

## SKILLS

- Javascript
- HTML/CSS
- Materialize & Bootstrap
- Less & Sass
- AngularJS & React
- Node.js & Express.js
- JQuery

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Functional Programming
- RESTful API
- Google Maps & Places APIs
- Communication
- Client focus

# **PROJECTS**

#### **PROXIMO**

RESTAURANT DISCOVERY APP - USES GOOGLE API AND GEOLOCATION

#### **COVALENCE ECOMMERCE**

FROM-SCRATCH SHOPPING CART, FULLY-FUNCTIONAL CHECKOUT

#### **PERSONAL BLOG**

SESSION STORING, LIMITED RIGHTS PER ACCOUNT

### EXPERIENCE

#### COVALENCE FULL-STACK DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

STUDENT | OCT 2017 - DEC 2017

- · Completed over 500 hours of coding
- · Worked alone and in groups
- · Practiced time management, creative collaboration

#### HUMANA, INC.

CONSULTANT, ANALYST | FEB 2013 - SEP 2017

- Tested and maintained databases and data flows used for analytics
- Co-chaired the department's career development committee, creating content and managing a Sharepoint site
- Received a special company award for outstanding project testing, resulting in shortening our close process by 20%
- Led regional pricing meetings, arbitrating between sales, contractors, and provider representatives to ensure companywide consistency and accuracy

# EDUCATION

#### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ECONOMICS**

UNIVERSITY OF LOUISVILLE | 2008 - 2013 FOCUS ON MATHS: PROBABILITY, STATISTICS, ACTUARIAL